A Guide to the Zona Gale Collection
University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library, #7763-a
Zona Gale Collection 1914-1937
University of Virginia. Library. Special Collections Dept. Alderman Library University of Virginia Charlottesville, Virginia 22903 USA
7763-a
20 items
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open to research.
Acquisition Information
Purchase 1968 Apr 21
Item Listing
- Letters
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1921 Apr 16; ALS, 4 p.
    [Declines invitation to come to New York with her mother at this time of year; promises to see him there in May.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1921 Jun 6; ALS, 3 p.
    [Expresses gratitude for
    The Growth of the Soil
    compares it to an advanced course in English literature; describes country spring in Wisconsin. ]
  - Zona Gale to Mabel Beeman Curran, 1921 Oct 13; ALS, 3 p.
    [Discusses royalties; mentions
    Uncle Jimmy
    , published in the 1921 October
    Ladies Home Journal
    . ]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1922 Jan 28; ALS, 4 p.
    [Thanks him for sending her
    The Mind in the Making
    gives a short review of the book; mentions her illness.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1922 Nov 18; ALS, 4 p.
    [Expresses hope that he has returned from Europe; speaks in gratitude of his idea to syndicate her articles and editorials; mentions that her next novel,
    Faint Perfume
    , will be serialized with the
    Century Magazine
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1923 Mar 4; APCS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for flowers.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1925 Jan 25; ALS, 1 p.
    [Refers to her ancestors.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1925 Nov 26; TLS w/AN, 1 p.
    [Expresses thanks; hopes to see him in Madison; mentions the Glenn Franks.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, 1926 Dec 22; ALS, 4 p.
    [Sends Christmas and New Year wishes and appreciation that he will put in a word about her book to a foreign publisher.]
  - Zona Gale[Breese] to Edward A. Filene, 1933 Nov 23; TLS, 1 p.
    [Mentions the Forum in Boston and a speaking engagement in New York. ]
  - Zona Gale to Miss Schoedler, 1936 Jul 14; ALS, 2 p.
    [Mentions Camp Franklin near Woodruff and Minocqua, where Edward A. Filene is considering a vacation.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, n. y. Jun 8; ALS, 4 p.
    [Counsels him on his upcoming trip to Europe; urges him to see Switzerland; expresses her love for that country.]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, n. y. Nov 17; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions their ten-day stay in New York and her fascination with the city.]
  - Zona Gale to Mr. Tooley, n. y. Nov 26; ALS, 1 p.
    [Mentions enclosure of a statement of hers to Mr. de Mille; promises to send a photograph as soon as she arrives in Wisconsin. ]
  - Zona Gale to Edward A. Filene, n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Thanks him for sending a "mascotte," and for his hospitality to her and her mother.]
  - Zona Gale to Miss Bate[s], n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [Apologizes for replying late; expresses pleasure that she will see her on Thursday.]
  - Zona Gale to Miss Bate[s], n. d.; ALS, 2 p.
    [invites her to spend time with her before a dinner engagement.]
  - Zona Gale to Miss McComas, n. d.; ANS, 1 p.
    [Letter of introduction for Edward A. Filene. ]
  - Zona Gale to unknown, n. d.; APCS, 1 p.
    [Discusses the Glenwood Mission Inn, Riverside, California. ]